# **Todd Sutherland**Front End Developer/Designer

Front End
HTML5/CSS3
Sass/LESS
Bootstrap
jQuery
WordPress

**Design**PhotoShop
Illustrator
InDesign

**Back End**PHP7
MySQL/MariaDB
Xampp/Apache
Node.js

#### **Online Portfolio**

www.toddsutherlanddesigns.com

**Address**Wollongong,
Sydney Australia

Mobile

+61 4 10 636 052

**Email** 

sutho100@gmail.com

# **Work History**

# Front End and Designer at ThinkZion (2016 - current)

JavaScript/HTML5/CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP7, SourceTree, Git, Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Visual Studio, SASS/LESS, Koala CSS preprocessor

# CNC Machinist/Designer at Broens industries (2007 - 2016)

AutoCAD, Inventor, Solidworks and Mastercam

## **Education**

Diploma of Interactive Digital Media (web & mobile) (2016 - Current) CNC CAD/CAM (2015 - 2016) Certificate 4 for Mechanical Engineering (Fitting Machining) (2007 - 2011)

#### **Recent Clients**

## **Kosrae Nautilus Resort (Feb 2017)**

Making international headlines after it was raffled off in July 2016 to two lucky Australians, the resort has enjoyed a very successful new website launch in February 2017. We boosted user base by over 800% at launch and reduced bounce rate dramatically by over 50%

## **GNSS Monitoring (Oct 2016)**

Advanced live CSV data Graphing and Map Integration

## **Kosrae Diving (Mar 2017)**

The sister site of the international headlining Kosrae Nautilus Resort we recently launched, offering a more in-depth island wide guide from under the surface of the ocean

## **Summary**

I'm an enthusiastic Front End Developer/Designer currently studying my passion at SAE Qantm. I've had real world experience working on an array of projects including building and maintaining Kosrae Nautilus resort and diving websites

JavaScript/HTML5/CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP7, WordPress, SourceTree, GitHub, Version Control, Google Analytics, Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Visual Studio, Sublime Text, SASS/LESS, Koala CSS preprocessor, Project Management, Customer Relations

At Broen Industries, a precision aerospace company, I have worked with several departments including CNC machining, design and fitting. Each role has offered me a different skill set - including operating different machines - requiring knowledge of programming and software

# References

| Joel Dobbins    | Senior UI Developer at Macquarie Group               | +61 4 20 445 946 |
|-----------------|--|------------------|
| Gavin Wilkinson | Communications Officer at The Royal Sydney Golf Club | +61 432 158 108  |
| Paul Baker      | Application Engineer at Okuma Australia              | +61 4 21 688 212 |
| Paul Symons     | Co-founder of GNSS Monitoring                        | +61 4 01 742 814 |